Of all the abductions, this one is different.
Bugonia is a science fiction, thriller, crime film directed by Yorgos Lanthimos.
Two conspiracy obsessed young men kidnap the high-powered CEO of a major company,
convinced that she is an alien intent on destroying planet Earth.
Michelle, played by Emma Stone.
Teddy, played by Jesse Plemons.
Don, played by Aidan Delbis.
Casey, played by Stavros Halkias.
Sandy, played by Alicia Silverstone.
Ricky / Security Guard, played by J. Carmen Galindez Barrera.
Bugonia is a 2025 black comedy film directed by Yorgos
Lanthimos and written by Will Tracy.
An English-language remake of the 2003 South Korean film Save the Green Planet!
by Jang Joon-hwan, Bugonia follows two young men who kidnap a powerful CEO,
suspecting that she is secretly an alien who wants to destroy Earth.
A co-production of the United Kingdom, Ireland, South Korea, and the United States, the film stars
Emma Stone, Jesse Plemons, Aidan Delbis, Stavros Halkias, and Alicia Silverstone.
Development on the film began in 2020, with Jang attached to direct, Will Tracy
adapting the screenplay, and Ari Aster boarding as producer.
Jang later stepped down as director, citing health concerns,
but remained attached as an executive producer.
By February 2024, Lanthimos was hired to direct in Jang's place, while
Stone joined the project both as an actress and producer.
Plemons joined the cast that May, and it was soon acquired by Focus
Features for distribution at the Cannes Film Festival.
Principal photography began in July in High Wycombe, England, and Atlanta,
Georgia, and during which time, the rest of the cast was announced.
Additional filming took place in May 2025 in Milos, Greece.
With an estimated budget of $45–$55 million, Bugonia
is Lanthimos's most expensive film.
Bugonia premiered in the main competition of the 82nd Venice International Film Festival on August 28,
2025, and was theatrically released in the United States by Focus Features on October 24.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, with the
performances of Stone and Plemons receiving praise.
Both received nominations for their performances at the 83rd
Golden Globe Awards and the 32nd Actor Awards.
At the 98th Academy Awards, the film received four nominations
including Best Picture and Best Actress for Stone.
The film explores themes of saving the world,
capitalism, kidnapping, paranoia, delusion.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.